hey English Learners welcome to this A1
English listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and learn new words and
phrases today we're going to talk about
having balance it's important to have
balance in our lives if we don't have
this we might be really stressed or we
might not achieve our goals before we
start remember to download my free
listening Time podcast on Spotify Apple
podcasts or on any other podcast app so
you can practice your English the link
is in the description below okay let's
talk about having balance finding
balance in life means making choices
that keep us healthy and happy let's
talk about how to do this in different
parts of our Lives first of all it's
important to have a balance between work
and fun work is necessary we need to
work to make money provide for our
family and because it's good to be
productive we also need to have fun too
it's essential to laugh play spend time
with others and enjoy life it's
important to work and have fun if we
only work without any fun we can become
tired and unhappy but if we only want to
have fun we can't do our work so we need
to find a balance we should work hard
and also dedicate some time to
relaxation and fun this balance helps us
finish our tasks and stay happy now
let's talk about organizing our day it's
good to make plans and organize your
schedule if you do this you'll know what
you need to do every day it will help
you stay on track and get things done
planning also helps us have more time to
do things during the day however we
don't want to always plan everything
it's also nice to have a little Freedom
what I mean is giving yourself the
opportunity to do something things
without planning them first sometimes
it's good to do what feels right at that
moment this keeps life interesting so I
think it's good to plan our days but
also allow ourselves to do some things
that we didn't plan this balance helps
us be productive and organized but also
happy and less stressed lastly let's
talk about about eating healthy of
course we should all try to eat healthy
food if we don't take care of our health
we can have serious problems eating
healthy makes us feel better and it also
helps us work better and relax better
but sometimes we want to eat things that
aren't so healthy for example I often
crave sweets eating a lot of this type
of food isn't so good however if we only
eat this food sometimes it's not as bad
this is the balance that I think we
should have we should eat healthy most
of the time but also allow ourselves to
cheat a little bit then after we cheat
and eat something unhealthy we should
immediately go back to eating healthy
again this balance helps us stay healthy
but also lets us enjoy our favorite
treats once in a while as you can see
balance is key finding balance in these
areas of life makes life more enjoyable
we can do the things that are necessary
like working hard and eating healthy but
also enjoy our lives this is balance
well that's all for today I hope this
listening practice video was helpful for
you remember to download my free
listening Time Podcast if you want to
improve your listening in English the
link is down below and you can also sign
up for my membership if you want my
listening practice seminars which will
help you understand fast English that
link is also down below all right thank
you for watching and I'll see you in the
next
video